

RYAN HALL

Senior VMware Administrator



Kansas City, MC



(209)740-3903



Ryan.Hall0203@gmail.com



ryanofkansas.com

github.com/JamesonL33T,

COMPENTENCIES

Windows

Server

FSXi

6.0/6.5/6.7

vCenter .

6.5/6.7<mark>/</mark>7.0

Active

5145

DITICE

LICC

HPE

Linux

NSY-V

VC A NI

LAN/WAN

AWS

VROP:

Citrix

Basic

HTML,CSS,J

Node,Reac

MongoD

Ansible

CERTIFICATIONS

VCP-DCV 2019

VCP7-DTM

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS Certified Solution
Architect Associate

ITIL v4 Foundation

ABOUT ME

Systems Engineer with an MBA and over 8 years of IT experience. I am currently working as a VMware Administrator under contract with the USDA. I have two VCP certifications from VMware, I have recently become a certified AWS Solutions Architect Associate, ITIL v4 Foundations certification and I have an active Public Trust clearance. I have worked in large, medium, and small environments so I am familiar with every kind of workload. References are available upon requests.

WORK HISTORY

Oecember 2019 - Present

VMWARE ADMINISTRATOR CRITERION SYSTEMS

Contractor for USDA responsible for System Lifecycle management for all equipment, including planning, implementation, maintenance, upgrades, consolidation, and decommissioning of enterprise hardware, and software. Responsible for the maintenance of 200+ ESXi hosts across multiple vCenters. I helped upgrade vCenters from vCenter 6.5 to 6.7 and from 6.7 to 7.0. I Have upgraded hosts from ESXi 6.5 to 6.7. Performed multiple vSphere security patches. Updated Firmware and drivers on Cisco UCS and Cisco Fabric Interconnects. Help maintain VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) for disaster recovery.

May 2018 – December 2019

VIRTUALIZATION ENGINEER CERNER CORPORATION

Performed daily operations tasks across storage, network, and systems to verify system integrity and availability. Implement monitoring for virtual infrastructure and servers, and respond to alarms in a timely manner, preventing client impact and performance degradation. In this role I helped Cerner to scale and transition the team. Deployed vCenter, PSC, VUM, vROM, NSX, VSAN, and ESXi 6.5/6.7 components and infrastructure. Perform administrator tasks on over 2000 ESXi hosts. Completed assigned incident management tasks, Deploy, setup, and maintain testing environments, Provided Tier III and other support per service request.

July 2015 – May 2018

SYSTEMS ENGINEER CERNER CORPORATION

Primary point of contact for the client and lead troubleshooting activities and resolving system interface issues on the HIE platform for data connections. Completed assigned incident management tasks, setup, maintain environments, provide Tier III and other support per service request. Performed various application installations and maintenance on backend and frontend systems (Windows/Linux).

June 2013 – June 2015

SERVER SYSTEMS ENGINEER YRCW

Windows server administrator responsible for VMware Administration. Worked with DNS, DHCP, WSUS, the maintenance of VMware ESXi hosts, physical servers and virtual machines. Performed driver and firmware updates and server maintenance on HPE and Dell servers.

October 2012 – December 2014

OFFICE ADMINISTRATOR TENNEY PEDIATRICS

Part Time Windows Small Business Server and Network Administrator responsible for installation, maintenance, troubleshooting and support of Windows based desktop/server related network systems. Monitored and

SOCIAL



maintained Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, SQL Server and domains. Performed and managed backups.

March 2008 - March 2011

DISTRIBUTION PROCESS WORKER DLA DDJC

Received, managed, stowed, inventoried, packed and shipped $\,$ various materials around the world for various military and government agencies.

October 2003 – July 2007

UNITED STATES ARMY

Conducted inventory of stock daily to ensure accuracy Responsible for all research, storage, accountability, and accuracy of all items associated with the arms room.

EDUCATION

April 2020

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY

MBA, IT Management

December 2013

ITT TECHNICAL INSTITUTE

Bachelor of Science degree in Information Systems Security